Sasuke's Story: Sunrise,
Part 3: Fuushin
な… なんだ!?
What is that?!
(サスケ)そいつから離れろ！
Get away from him!
So that's the Sharingan.
(エン)あれが 写輪眼。
(大蛇丸)あのサスケ君が→
What a surprise.
Sasuke using his Sharingan
to save someone's life…
写輪眼を使って
人助けなんて 驚きね。
Huh?
W-Watch out!
やばいって…。
うわ～！ どうしたんだ!?
What happened?!
うわ…。
ヒメユリ様！
Lady Himeyuri!
だから… なんなんだよ!?
Just what is going on?
Leave one of them to me!
(ヤマト)１人は任せて！
(ヤマト)救うことはできないけど
被害の拡大は防げる。
We can't save them…
but we can lessen the damage!
面倒くさいわね。
How bothersome.
(チノ)キャーッ！
Chino!
チノ！
どうした？
What is it?
(チノ)サスケちゃんが
助けてくれるなんて…。
I didn't expect you to save me…
Sasuke dear.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
(ノワキ)チノ！
Chino!
Are you okay?
(ノワキ)大丈夫だったか？
(チノ)平気 平気！ イタッ…。
I'm fine, I'm fine... Ow!
手当てが必要だな。
アチャー！
You need to get that taken care of.
今のが 木ノ葉を襲撃したという
起爆人間…。
They're the Exploding Humans that
attacked the Hidden Leaf Village.
やっかいな相手だね。
They're quite troublesome.
I can't make contact with him,
so I'm going to get going.
彼と接触するわけには
いかないんで 僕は消えるよ。
御屋城には会えそうにないわね。
なんだと!?
Looks like you won't get
to meet Oyashiro.
What?
言ったでしょ？
用心深い男だって。
I told you, didn't I?
He's a very cautious man.
こんな騒ぎがあったあとで
姿を現すとは考えにくいし→
I can't imagine he'd stick around
after all this uproar.
試合が途中で終わった以上
手札譲渡が行われることもない。
And since the match
ended midway,
there won't be an ID tag
transfer ceremony either.
Besides, we won't be able
to get any intel on Fuushin,
つまり サスケ君は
起爆人間を作り出してる→
who belonged to
Oyashiro's former guard unit,
元御屋城の護衛団にいた→
風心とかいう男の情報も
得られない。
who's making all
these Exploding Humans.
This has been
a total waste of time.
すべては ムダ骨だったってこと。
大蛇丸様。
Lord Orochimaru.
なんですって？ サスケ君…。
What did you say?
Sasuke…
御屋城が
あなたを呼んでるんですって。
Oyashiro is asking for you.
行っといでよ。
お前は？
Go on ahead.
What about you?
I'm going to get
this wound looked at.
私は
ケガの手当てをしてもらってくる。
I'll stick with Chino.
俺は チノに付き添う。
わかった。
All right.
(エン)あ… こんちは！
僕 御屋城エン。
Oh, hello!
I am En Oyashiro.
よろしくね！
Nice to meet you!
本当に こいつが御屋城エンなのか？
間違いないわ。
Is he really En Oyashiro?
There's no mistake.
It's been a long time,
Mr. Orochimaru!
お久しぶり！ 大蛇丸さん。
When was the last time
we were face to face like this?
(大蛇丸)いつ以来かしらね？
こうして顔を突き合わせるのは。
さぁ？
久々すぎて 忘れちゃいました。
It's been so long,
I don't remember.
What's going on?
だけど どういう風の吹き回し？
あなた こんなに あっさり
人前に顔を出す→
I don't recall you
being someone
who'd reveal himself so casually
before others like this.
不用心な人間だっけ？
おもしろいものを
見せてもらいましたから。
It's only because I witnessed
something very interesting.
Though it was quite a shock to
see humans explode like that.
(エン)でも 人間が爆発したのには
びっくりしたよ。
あれでしょ？
木ノ葉の里を襲った起爆人間って。
They're just like
the Exploding Humans
that attacked
the Hidden Leaf, right?
知っているのか？
You know about that?
情報に疎いと
この商売やっていけないから。
You can't be in
my line of business
if you're not on top of the news.
あれって キミを狙って
現れたんだよね？
They appeared because
they were after you, right?
今回のは そうかもしれない。
Perhaps, this time.
今回のってことは…。
This time?
木ノ葉の里は
別の目的で襲われたってこと？
Are you saying that they attacked
the Hidden Leaf Village
for a different purpose?
だって そうなるよね？
I mean, doesn't it seem like it?
《木ノ葉を襲ったのも
俺が目的だった？》
They attacked the Hidden Leaf Village
with me as their target?
起爆人間を作っているやつが
お前の護衛団にいたらしい。
The man creating
the Exploding Humans
seems to be a former member
of your guard unit.
えっ ウッソ！
風心という。
What? No way!
His name is Fuushin.
知っているな？
へぇ あの子が。
You know him, don't you?
Hmm… That kid?
元は
よその子だったんだけどね。
He initially belonged to someone else.
よその子？
コロシアムで勝ち取って→
Someone else?
I won him at the Coliseum and
assigned him to my guard unit.
うちの護衛団に入れたんだ。
生まれは水の国の
小さな島だったはずだよ。
I believe he was born on
a small island in the Land of Water.
島の人たちに恐れられて→
When he was young,
小さい頃に
売り飛ばされたんだって。
he was sold off by the islanders
because they were scared of him.
売り飛ばされた？
Sold off?
血継限界なんて
そんなもんじゃない？
Isn't that how it is with
the Kekkei Genkai?
特異な力なんて→
Weak humans who
consider themselves "normal"
自らを普通と称する
弱者にしてみれば→
恐怖でしかないでしょ。
always fear unusual power.
生まれ出た時点で
損してるようなもんだよね。
It's a disadvantage from
the moment you manifest it.
Though personally,
I like Kekkei Genkai.
僕は好きだけどね
血継限界。
だってほら 強いし
レア感があっていいじゃない！
I mean, they're powerful and rare!
That's why I've collected
all different kinds for my guard unit.
だから いろいろ集めて
護衛団に入れてたんだ。
レア度を上げるために
１人だけ残して→
I've even slaughtered the rest
皆殺しに
しちゃったこともあるけど ウフ！
and left only one to
increase the rarity…
The only thing is,
ただ 生まれが生まれだから
反抗的な子が多かったよ。
because of the difficult situations
surrounding their upbringing,
many of the kids were rebellious.
僕が医療忍術を
使えなかったら→
If I didn't know Medical Ninjutsu,
飼いならせなかっただろうね。
I probably couldn't
have tamed them.
風心は比較的
従順でいい子だったけど→
Fuushin was a relatively good kid,
ある日 突然 他の子たち連れて
逃げ出しちゃったんだ。
but one day out of the blue,
he took the other kids and ran away.
な～んで
逃げちゃったんだろうな？
I wonder why he ran away?
毎日エサあげてたし
お小遣いもあげてたのに。
I fed them every day and
even gave them an allowance.
もういい。
あ。
I've heard enough!
風心は赤眼を持っていたか？
Did Fuushin have red eyes?
Red eyes?
(エン)赤眼？
ああ ああ そういえば→
Oh, now that you mention it…
あ～ 風心と逃げた中に
そういうの持ってる子いたっけな。
One of the kids who ran away with
Fuushin had eyes like that.
風心と逃げた？
Ran away with Fuushin?
《ならば 風心には仲間が…。
So Fuushin has a partner?
あの幻術トラップは
そいつの仕業か》
Was that Genjutsu Trap
his doing?
名前は？
What was his name?
う～ん 忘れちった。
I've forgotten.
思い出せ。
ああ 厳しいねぇ。
Then remember.
You're so harsh!
う～ん… ああ そうそう。
Oh, I know!
その子 たしか
血之池一族だったっけ？
That kid was from the Chinoike Clan.
血之池一族？
なんだ それは？
The Chinoike Clan?
What is that?
悲しい話だよ。
It's a tragic story.
構わない 話してくれ。
I don't care, tell me.
それは 千手柱間や うちはマダラが→
It goes way back…
Even before the time Hashirama Senju
and Madara Uchiha competed for power.
しのぎを削っていたときよりも
更に前の話。
赤い血に濡れた目
血龍眼を持つ血之池一族。
Bloodshot eyes…
The Chinoike Clan with
their Ketsuryugan.
雷の国に住んでいた彼らは
特に幻術に長け→
They lived in
the Land of Lightning.
They were especially proficient
with genjutsu
その瞳術に捕らわれたら最後→
and once you were caught
in their Visual Jutsu,
逃れることはできないと
言われていた。
it was said
you could never escape.
そんな血之池一族の娘が→
Anyway, one of the Chinoike Clan
women was sent
雷の国の大名の側室として
嫁ぐことになった。
to become the concubine of
the feudal lord of the Land of Lightning.
気立てがよくて
美しい娘だったけど→
She was personable and beautiful…
それに正室が嫉妬した。
and that made the lord's consort
terribly jealous.
不幸なことに 大名は
娘を側室にしてからほどなく→
Unfortunately, shortly after taking
the girl as his concubine,
the feudal lord became ill and died.
病に倒れ 死んでしまう。
「この女が嫁いだせいだ！」
正妻は すべてを娘のせいにした。
"It's her fault he died!"
The lord's consort put all
the blame on the concubine.
そして 血之池一族の
特異な体質を知る→
And those who knew about
the Chinoike Clan's unusual genetics,
周囲の者たちは
正妻の言葉を鵜呑みにした。
supported the consort's claim.
その結果 娘は一族ごと
地獄谷という場所に追放された。
As a result, the girl and
her entire clan
was exiled to a place known
as Hell Valley.
その際
正妻が雇ったのが…。
And for that, the consort hired…
どうした？
What's the matter?
うちは一族。
The Uchiha Clan.
なんだと？
What did you say?
The Uchiha Clan with their Sharingan
were the only ones
特殊な瞳術を持つ
血之池一族に対抗できるのは→
who could go up against
the Chinoike Clan
写輪眼を持つ
うちは一族しかいない。
and their unique Visual Jutsu.
The Chinoike asked the Uchiha to set up
a meeting place to negotiate,
血之池は うちはに
話し合いの場所を求めたけど→
but were rejected.
聞き入れられなかったらしい。
木ノ葉で迫害され→
Seems the Uchiha Clan who suffered
long through persecution
苦しみ続けた
うちは一族もまた→
were also complicit in
the persecution of others.
誰かの迫害に
加担していたってわけね。
イタチは…。
What about Itachi?
イタチは
このことを知っていたのか？
Was Itachi aware of this?
さあ… ただ→
I wonder…
However…
地獄谷に行けば
何かわかるかもしれないわよ。
you may learn something
if you go to Hell Valley.
ん？
地獄谷は どこだ？
Where is Hell Valley located?
湯の国だよ。
It's in the Land of Steam.
(エン)行くの？
Are you going?
わからない。
I don't know.
I guess not.
だよね
風心がいるとは思えないし。
You don't know if Fuushin
is actually there.
けど 応援してるよ 頑張って。
But I'm rooting for you.
Good luck!
起爆人間なんて物騒なもの
とっとと始末してほしいから。
We need to get rid of nuisances like
Exploding Humans as soon as possible.
意外ね。
That's unusual.
I didn't expect to hear that from
a weapons trader like yourself.
武器商人のあなたから
そんな言葉が出るなんて。
こんな便利な爆弾が
流通しちゃったら→
If a convenient explosive like
that became commonplace,
I'd be forced to shut down
my business.
僕ら おまんまの
食い上げじゃないですか。
共犯者にすぎない。 そう言ったな。
Just as guilty…
That's what you said.
(チノ)え？
Huh?
((被害者にしてみれば
加害者も第三者も一緒。
To a victim, the assailant and
a third party are no different.
自分を救ってくれなかった人たち。
People are no better than the assailant
if they didn't try to help.
それで ひとくくり。
ここで行われている 金持ちどもの
道楽を止めることなく→
If you only pity the loser
同情的な言葉を口にするだけの
サスケちゃんだって→
and do nothing to stop
the decadence of the rich…
(共犯者にすぎないよ))
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
お前の言うとおりだ。 だが…。
It's just as you said.
But…
だが？
"But"?
いや なんでもない。
No, never mind.
あのさ どうせ
教えてくれないんだろうけど→
Hey, you probably won't tell me…
一応 聞いとくね。
But I'll ask anyway.
今度は どこに向かってんの？
Where are you headed this time?
地獄谷だ。
ほらね どうせ教えてくれない。
Hell Valley.
See? You didn't tell me…
って… 地獄谷!?
What? Hell Valley?!
そこに 起爆人間を
作ってるやつがいるのか？
The one making Exploding Humans
is there?
おそらく いない。
Probably not.
だったら 何しに行くの？
Then why are you going?
見ておきたい 地獄谷を。
I want to see this Hell Valley
with my own eyes.
うちは一族
最後の生き残りとして。
As the last survivor
of the Uchiha Clan.
(チノ)え～っ！
Huh?!
We came all the way here
to the Land of Steam,
はるばる湯の国まで来て→
and we're not gonna soak
in the hot springs?
温泉 入ってかないの!?
お前たちは好きにしろ。
You two can do
whatever you want.
ここからは別行動だ。
This is where we go
our separate ways.
But why?
別行動って どうして？
起爆人間を
作り出しているやつの狙いは→
The one making
the Exploding Humans is after me.
俺だ。
お前たちは
一緒にいないほうがいい。
It's better if
you're not around me.
ここまで一緒に来といて→
We came all the way here together.
サスケちゃんを１人にできると思う？
As if we'd desert you now,
Sasuke dear.
私たちも行くよ 地獄谷に。
We're going with you
to Hell Valley!
(チノ)キャーッ！
Exploding Humans!
起爆人間。
サスケちゃん！
Sasuke dear!
離れていろ！
Stay away!
Nowaki, let go!
ノワキ！ こら 離せ！
《チャクラを… まとっていない》
He's…
not cloaked in chakra.
うわっ！
Hot! So hot...!
アッチ～！
Hot! So hot!
お前 風心ではないな？
You're not Fuushin, are you?
なっ なに言ってやがる。
俺様は雷光団の…。
W-What're you saying?
I'm the Lightning Gang's…
I possess the Sharingan.
俺には写輪眼がある。
I can look into
your memories with this.
これを使えば
お前の記憶を覗ける。
ウソだった場合 命は保障しない。
If you're lying, I can't guarantee
that I'll spare you.
わかったよ。
Fine.
命は保障しないだ？
Won't guarantee my life?
その言葉
そっくり返させてもらうぜ。
Well, I'll say it right back at you!
と やらせねえよ！
Whoa... I won't let you.
土遁 土流壁！
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
熔遁 護謨壁！
Lava Style: Rubber Wall!
ゴムは雷遁に強ぇんだぜ。
Rubber is strong against
the Lightnin
熔遁 護謨鞠！
さ～てと いくぜ！
こっからだ！
んだと！
だったら数を増やしてやるぜ！
天照！
な なんだこれ！
うっ き 消えねえ！
熱っ アチー！
な なんでもしゃべる！
しゃべります。
しゃべらせていただきます。
だから この火を消してくれ！
加具土命。
ハァ ハァ ふぅ。
しゃべらなくていい。
((カリュウ : 力を借りたい 風心。
待っててくれ 頭。
そのサスケってやつに→
(俺が狙ってると
思い込ませればいいのか？))
やはりな。
そうだよ。
俺を狙ったチャクラ刀は→
竹の村でお前が投げたチャクラ刀と
同じものだった。
正体を現せ。
正体？
それは お前の本当の姿ではない。
でなければ
竹の村のイオウ老人の前に→
出られるはずがない。
それでも さすがに
御屋城エンに会うのは怖かったか？
クッ…。
(風心)いかにも
これが俺の本当の姿だよ。
風心。